Sanjaya Shrestha

Web Developer

West Des Moines, IA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Sanjaya-Shrestha/3fafd5feac3b416e

Took an instrumental role in the full software development lifecycle for diverse applications; worked with the project manager on research and analysis of business problems, company requirements, and stakeholder expectations. Designed solutions prototypes and tested against design specifications in both development and production environments. Innovated unique, flexible, user-friendly front-end interfaces, with features to improve interactivity. Handled development of databases and stored procedures. Coordinated all back-end programming. Addressed software or requirements issues as needed.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE

Web Developer

WEB CREATION NEPAL PVT. LTD - Kathmandu, NP - 2014 to 2016

CAREER NOTE: Completed on-campus studies and currently taking distance education courses to complete a Master's Degree in Computer Science (Available for full-time, W-2 employment).

WEB CREATION NEPAL PVT. LTD., Kathmandu, Nepal • 2014-2016

IT service provider offering engineering, development, design, SEO, and marketing services to global clients.

Web Developer

Took an instrumental role in the full software development lifecycle for diverse applications; worked with the project manager on research and analysis of business problems, company requirements, and stakeholder expectations. Designed solutions prototypes and tested against design specifications in both development and production environments. Innovated unique, flexible, user-friendly front-end interfaces, with features to improve interactivity. Handled development of databases and stored procedures. Coordinated all back-end programming. Addressed software or requirements issues as needed.

Projects:

- Nirogi Nepal Project: A web based application for online disease and health management, with PHP for the back-end and MySQL for the database.
- Nims Drugs Project: A web based application for tracking drugs used in preparation of specific medications.
- Mridaya Project: A web shop application for purchasing from different stores.
- Koshi International Services Project: A web application for managing CMS and advertising job posts.
- Cell Store Project: A web application for managing cell phones based on brand, and showing total price for selected cell repair.

Technologies: Spring MVC, Spring Boot, JSP, Servlet, PHP, Codeigniter, MySQL, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, AJAX, JavaScript, jQuery.

Web Developer

E-MULTITECH SOLUTION PVT. LTD - Kathmandu, NP - 2012 to 2014

Kathmandu, Nepal • 2012-2014

Provider of creative, user-friendly web design, web development, and mobile app services.

Web Developer

Analyzed project requirements and developed system architecture design, including prototype creation, research, issue resolution, and performance enhancement. Implemented user interfaces, back-end functionality, modules, and reporting systems.

Projects:

• Random Chat: A web-based application allowing users to connect with others and manage their account on an online platform.

• Yep Bid: A web-based application providing bidding and auction services.

Technologies: PHP, Codelgniter, Jsp, Servlet, Spring MVC, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, AJAX, JavaScript, jQuery, MySQL.

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Computer Science in distance education

Maharishi University of Management - Fairfield, IA April 2019

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Engineering in Software Engineering

Kathmandu Engineering College - Kathmandu, NP 2012

SKILLS

AJAX (5 years), Bootstrap (5 years), HTML5 (5 years), JavaScript (5 years), jQuery. (5 years), Java (4 years), CSS (4 years), JSON (4 years), PHP (4 years), MySQL (4 years), Spring (4 years)

LINKS

https://www.linkedin.com/in/sanjaya-shrestha

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

CORE COMPETENCIES

Java Programming • Front-End Development • Web Application Programming • Back-End Development Requirements Gathering & Analysis • User Interface Design • Database Development • Troubleshooting

Languages: Java, PHP, C++, C

Web: JSP, Servlet, JQuery, JavaScript, Bootstrap, HTML, HTML5, CSS3, AJAX, PHP, WordPress, JPA,

Angular JS, React JS

Web Services: Restful, JSON

Web/ App Servers: Tomcat, Glassfish

Databases: MySQL, SQL

Frameworks: Spring, Hibernate, JSF, Codelgniter

Design Patterns: MVC, Singleton, Factory

SDLC: Waterfall, Agile

Tools: Eclipse, STS, NetBeans, Dreamweaver, PHPDesigner, GIT, Maven

Platforms: Windows